<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Association of Arbours Psychotherapists]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[The Association of Arbours Psychotherapists]]></description>
        <link>http://aapmembers.org/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 23:42:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://aapmembers.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 23:42:21 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AAP Spring 2017 Lecture]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1><strong>AAP Spring 2017 Lecture</strong></h1>,<h1><strong>Whither Psychiatry - David Bell</strong></h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/94eada76-e568-4d3f-981d-b9a9c834db9a.jpg" title="Dr David Bell" alt="David Bell Psychiatrist">,<p>All cultures develop their own modes of selfexplanation, but such explanations, somewhat like symptoms, inevitably conceal as much as they reveal.<br>In this sense psychoanalysis may be well placed to enter into a critical relationship with the forms of consciousness that characterise our age. The ideology of the market has so penetrated into social consciousness that it appears as "normality", but this normality can be problematic.<br>The presentation will, then, fall into two parts. In the first some broad socio-cultural considerations will be offered as regards our contemporary world with an emphasis on its impact upon mental health. <br>Special reference will then be made to the work of the Fitzjohn's Unit, a specialist service based within the Adult Department of the Tavistock Clinic, that provides a unique psychotherapeutic treatment for patients enduring severe psychiatric disorders. The lecture will then focus on the deterioration in psychiatric care. This deterioration creates an environment which is increasingly hostile to the kind of thinking that psychoanalysis represents.<br>This latter part should hopefully be understood in the context of the former exploration.</p>,<p>Dr. David Bell is past President of the British Psychoanalytic Society.</p>,<p>He is a Consultant psychiatrist at the Tavistock where he directs a Specialist Unit (the Fitzjohn’s Unit) for serious/enduring complex disorders. In 2012-2013 he was Visiting Professorial Fellow at Birkbeck College, London. His writing and lecturing interests include the development of psychoanalytic concepts, psychosis and borderlines states. Throughout his professional career he has been deeply involved in the relation between psychoanalysis and other disciplines: literature, philosophy, culture and socio-political issues and has published extensively in these areas. His publications include: “Paranoia, psychoanalysis and Culture”, “Reason and Passion”, “Living on the Border”. He is one of the UK’s leading psychiatric experts in asylum and human rights.</p>,<p><a href="http://www.melanie-klein-trust.org.uk/bell" title="bibliography">Here is a short bibliography from the Melanie Klein Trust.</a></p>,<a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/whither-psychiatry-david-bell-aap-spring-2017-lecture-tickets-32833276213" data-role="cta">Book now on Eventbrite</a>,<a href="https://aapmembers.org/cominglecture/" data-role="cta">Further Detail and Directions</a>]]></description>
            <link>http://aapmembers.org/aap-spring-lecture/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">59fbfeae-3b4f-40b9-ad28-f6e0812d86cd</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 17:30:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Booking]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/64bcc418-a25d-4cc8-8883-16fe991dc419.jpg" title="Civilisation And Its Discontents">,<h1><strong>Booking</strong></h1>,<h2><strong>The early bird reduction is for tickets</strong><br><strong>paid by 20th April 2017.</strong></h2>]]></description>
            <link>http://aapmembers.org/booking/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a6e30317-d397-42dd-a2ad-16ec4d842a81</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 23:38:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[About this website]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1><strong>About this website</strong></h1>,<p>The <strong>Association of Arbours Psychotherapists</strong> is the professional association for therapist who have trained with <strong><a href="http://arboursassociation.org/" title="The Arbours Association">The Arbours Association</a></strong>.</p>,<p>We are responsible for holding the registration of our members, the relationship between our professional body and others, in particular our immediate umbrella organisation CPJA (<a href="http://www.cpja.org.uk/">Council for Psychoanalysis and Jungian Analysis</a>) and the UKCP (<a href="http://www.psychotherapy.org.uk/">UKCP</a>).</p>,<p>We take an active interest in ethics, access to psychotherapy services both in terms of cost, physical access and “equal opportunity”, that is to say promoting understanding therapy without excluding preconceptions or prejudice. We encourage the engagement of our members in developing their own practices.</p>,<p>We organise various continued professional development (CPD) events including a public lecture series.</p>,<p>The forthcoming lecture on 26 November is <strong>Psychoanalysis and Politics</strong> given by <strong>David Morgan</strong>. Further details can be found here.</p>,<p>————</p>,<a href="http://aapmembers.org/aap-annual-conference/" data-role="cta">Annual Lecture</a>,<p>————</p>,<p>The lecture series since November 2014 is detailed here.</p>,<p>————</p>,<a href="http://aapmembers.org/lecture-series" data-role="cta">Lecture Series</a>,<p>————</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://aapmembers.org/about-this-website/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ff5bc65d-1330-4cc7-a37f-cf5e22612012</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 18:14:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>